Hello, programmer. Welcome back to our SQL tutorial series. Today I'm going to explore the insert
into statement in SQL, which is used to add a new record to the table. So first of all,
just simple definition for the SQL insert into statement. So the insert into statement in SQL
allows us to add new record to the table. It's a fundamental operation when working with the
database. And so let's explore for how it works with some example. Okay. So first of all,
here inserting the single record. Okay. So in this example, just adding a new employee table
or the new employees in the employees table. Okay. So previously, I have created the employees
now. I can create the insert new table in the employee. So now just go ahead again and here
just create for the employee table column information. So first, create the employee ID,
primarily first name, last name, age department, and here the hiring date. Okay. And now just
inserting the single record. So just go here. First of all, you just type insert into
insert for the table name, suppose like the employee. And here, give it for the parents. Okay.
And simply here define for this is already here and define this is must be used for the
employee ID. Okay. So now just take again the employee ID. So first of all, here, this is the employee
ID, then pair this type, the first name, the first name, then the last name. So here, type the
last name. And also here, creating for the age column. And next here, create for the department.
And also here, create for the hiring date. Okay. So now here, completely inserted for
the column and the next step here insert for the sample value. So first of all, define for
is the employee ID, suppose is one. And the next step here, I can create for the employee name,
Johan. And the next step here, create for the employee last name for the Smith. And then here,
define for the cases 31. And also for here, I can define for the department of the ID. Okay.
So now here, it is called the single inserting here, the new record with the employee table,
with the values of the first name, last name, department and the hiring date specified. And
this query will add new employees name like Johan. And then select, okay, and it will execute now.
So you can see here, insert it for the column. So now I can just check again for
here, I can create for the employee ID, the last name, department and also here, type for the
hiring date. Okay. So now here, remove all this hiring date. Again, they are simply create. So
now I can just select and click. And you can see here, this the on job is perfectly affected.
So here, completely created for the single inserting the job. So now change and first of all,
we are create, select the star from the returning for the employee table on the information.
So this is where the employee is, okay. So we can define for the employee.
So now just select and execute, you can see here, it is completely created for the employee ID,
first name and the last name, then the department here, you can see here, the priority is null,
because I have not inserted the sample data query. Okay. So next step here, inserting for the
multiple objectives. Okay. So now just go for here. First of all, I can copy these data query.
And then going for the next step. So first of all, I have used the three columns. Okay.
So next step here, I can create this and remove all this. Okay. So in this column,
I can just remove. And here, I can create for state is comma and again.
And next, I can just change for the name. So first of all, here, I can create for the employee ID
to three and four and change for the name here, insert for the name is James for Smith and
is the 25 and different for the 25 and also here, insert for the department of page.
And next step here, I can create for the file and change for here, insert the name is
in this file and also here, change for the last name for Johan song. Okay.
Now also insert the age, 35 and department of the finance. Okay.
And lastly, here, I can add another table of rows. So here, insert name is
Emily. So the Emily and lastly, Mr Brown, the stripe disease,
perfectly here, the Brown and age is insert for 20 age. And also here, I can be find for the department
of the marketing. Okay. So now this, I'm perfectly create the marketing department. So
the stripe, the marketing design, perfect. And here, I can create the design. So here,
inserting for the new three, recording to the entire table. So the specified values for the
company. So now this query, just second check. First of all, here, I can select an execute. Now,
you can see here, completely, completely query affected. Okay. And this query had the
James Smith to the age department, because Johan is in the finance department. So
this is the similar. And here, we can just execute. And you can see here, perfectly,
the age department, because Johan is in the finance department and Emily is the marketing
department. Okay. So here, completely done. The multiple products and service. So next step here,
I create this slide is the another sample. So here, I can create inserting record with the
different values. Okay. So first of all, I have just go and then here, I can create for the
default values for the column when inserting the records. Okay. And now just let's see how it works.
So first of all, I can create for the employee ID first and then the last name. And also here,
define that. This is the higher date. Okay. So just type the higher underscore.
So just check the date. So this is the hiring date. And then here, and now I can just remove the
two line, and then from this on now, just insert for dog was five. And insert for the Sarah,
and implement first name. It is called the Sarah. And the last name for Vincent. So Vincent and
insert for the writing tool. Okay. And here is department also, the department. Inserting here
economics. Okay. And then here, I have inserted for the hiring date is default. Okay.
So now we're this on perfectly created the default hiring date. So this example, inserting a new
record into the employee stable with the default value for the all column, except for the hiring
date. And just check for the hiring that's the first of all, I can select and then execute. Now,
you can see here, perfectly created and affected. And now just again, verify the employee table.
So first of all, select and execute. And you can see here, the default keyword is used to
indicate that the default value of the column should be used to fix. So you can see understanding.
So here, completely show for the employee table all the information. Okay. And there you have it.
Our view of the inserting statement is complete in SQL. We have provided some practical
example. Okay. So I hope you find this tutorial helpful. So stay tuned for more SQL tips and tricks.
So thank you for watching and happy calling.